You certainly enjoy your drink.
What happened this afternoon
was a disaster...
Behaving like like that in
front of so many people...
Still... that was the first
time a man ever protected me...
Personally, I think you're a lot more
personable than you were before.
I would've never believed that
there are nobles willing to risk
their safety for others.
I'm going to get more liquor.
It's probably the alcohol...
but this isn't so bad.
The Warrior Princess and the Barbaric King
Someone else protecting me...
No, no! What am I thinking?
Illodren's back!
Was that a child?
And Illdoren looked this way!
She spurted!
Hilarious.
D-Did I drink to the point
of hallucinating...?
It's Illdoren, Illdoren!
What a place to find Illdoren!
Wha... What...
What are these little things?!
I can see why you'd be surprised, Sera.
Veor! Where have you been since supper?
Actually, what are these little things?!
Now, now, there'll be time for that.
You're going to see something even
more surprising, soon enough.
So, this is the girl, Thundering Voice?
The one who defended people
from the Tsukebikeshi?
It takes real grit to
face a dragon head on.
I can see why she's
Thundering Voice's bride.
Being thankful for that's part
of why we're having this party.
It's a party! A party!
We've brought some of the
Sacred Tree's special liquor!
Yay!
Tiny people with wings, animated plants,
it's all so out of this world...
How bad are my hallucinations
going to get?!
Findin' a wife so soon is a
real cause for celebration!
It's the guidance of the Great Spirits!
Got somethin' for ya.
My way of sayin' congratulations.
Wh-Why would you give me something
as expensive as a sword?
Just be gracious and take it.
The swords from his forge
are all masterpieces.
That's not the issue!
If you're not convinced, take a look at
the blade. You'll want to keep it then.
The blade? I mean, I can discern
a sword's quality well enough...
Incredible.
She's a beaut, ain't she?
The blade itself is so consistent,
without a single distortion,
while being just thick enough,
with tasteful decorative fluting...
Is it enchanted? Balanced expertly
around the hilt, as well.
Not a single flaw... the wrapping
on the grip is so smooth and almost
seems to cling to the hand...
But more than anything, it gives
off this faint glow, like a pearl.
It's beautiful.
S'made from metal that only
we work: true silver alloy.
I hear the folks out
west call it "mythril."
Mythril...?
As in the same metal told of in the
Lord of the Armlets and Terminal Saga?
The same. In them western tall tales,
they apparently call us dwarves.
If I may, I'd like to make
the introductions here
that I called you all in for,
as the future great chief.
Three Wise Elders of the Quefto
Elder Vas
Elder Guas
Elder Balhath
These are the three wise
elders of the Quefto clan:
Elder Vas, Elder Guas, and Elder Balhath.
An Ixt Rijutsushi, Lord Karka Roth.
Ixt Rijutsushi
Karka Roth
Bud of the Sacred Tree
Nimhala
The Bud of the Sacred Tree, Lady Nimhala.
Great Chief of the Fairies
Vyufumec the Tornado
and her retinue
The Great Chief of the Fairies,
Lady Vyufumec and her servants.
Elves, spirits, and even fairies...
Are you all right, Sera?
Well, it's just... I didn't expect
anything more fantastical than a dragon.
Be that as it may, they clearly exist.
That's simply how it is.
Besides, they're not characters
from some fantasy story.
They're our dear neighbors.
You needn't feel so self-conscious.
Those from the west always react the
same way, so we're accustomed to it.
If anything, it's funny, so keep being
shocked! It goes well with the liquor.
Illdoren.
This leaf is good for overstimulation.
Has a sedative effect.
Th-Thank you?
Some people foam at the mouth
after taking it, though.
I can't deny their existence since
they're right in front of me,
but unlike dragons, being able to
converse with them is... a lot to take in!
This is a lot of new information,
considering I'd been fighting with
the eastern expedition for seven years.
Well, they make a point to avoid the west.
Why appear before me, then?
Didn't I tell you, earlier?
I arranged this meeting between
the elders of the various clans
so I could introduce you.
Now that you mention it...
I can see how you might have forgotten,
after the Tsukebikeshi attack.
The tribes they represent, along with us,
the oldest tribe of Cornem,
collectively form the Five Great Tribes.
The great chief, who moderates
conflicts between the five,
is chosen in a ritual
by the great spirits.
All manner of peoples, big and small,
are born in this land,
raised here, and live here,
before returning to the soil.
We have joined hands with each other
because we all understand
this course of nature.
The Tribal Alliance.
That's what those of us who
share a united culture,
under the Great Spirits, are called.
The Tribal Alliance...
Then the barbarians... no,
all these different races share
an equal cultural sphere?
Granted, unless there's
some kind of crisis...
we're mostly just drinking
buddies, as you can see!
This sounds more like a
party than an alliance.
Wait, you spoke of crisis.
What about Illodren's Eastern Expedition?
Why are you laughing?!
You'll have to forgive us, we don't
mean to make light of your question.
But the Tribal Alliance
doesn't get involved in territorial
disputes in the first place.
Uh... do you mean to tell me
that our war is being treated
with the same gravity as animals
fighting over territory?
We're not all that different from
animals, in the first place.
Besides, this alliance
wasn't created with the purpose of
suppressing other peoples in mind.
What is it for, then?
To respond to the threat of dragons?
Not that, either.
Our individual tribes can handle
most beasts and dragons.
Then there's some greater threat
that requires you to
seek each other's aid?
I don't want you to misunderstand.
Dragons are, without a question,
both clever and fierce.
However, they are not dreadful.
Dreadful...?
There is a type of monster...
we call them Fiends.
As you live here, you'll
encounter them sooner or later.
They're a bit like a living disaster.
Fiends...?
Compared to fighting those things,
I would die with a smile on
my face fighting Illdoren.
What?! That is genuinely scary!
Okay, enough! No more!
If we keep talking about those
blights, I'm gonna feel sick!
I thought this was a celebration!
She's right! Let's drink
and forget all about them!
Indeed.
A toast, to the new bride!
Here you go! I hope you enjoy it.
The Kufuwek have the most vitality
out of all people of these lands.
Consider yourself lucky.
O-Okay...
We may be seeing Thundering Voice's
child sooner than expected!
You give it your all, now!
Her backside looks like she'll
give him sturdy stock!
B-Backside...?!
Oh my!
Don't buy into their nonsense!
You're already acting like a married
couple of years! It's heartwarming.
I demand a smooch!
Smooch him! Smooch him! Smooch him!
There will be no smooches!
I'm surrounded by drunkards...
It's their way of giving
us their blessings.
They're as happy as they would
be if it was their own joy.
It's not just the liquor, either.
The clothes and necklace
you have are all gifts.
We spun your dress in our village.
The necklace is from us.
A mix of gold and mythril!
This, too? In addition to the sword?
This feller enchanted the sword.
It repairs itself, so you'll never
need to worry about maintenance.
That sort of thing is possible?
With Ixt sorcery, yes.
We all compensate for
the things the others lack.
The Cornem, for example,
offer our combat strength
in exchange for the goods
and technology that we lack.
I see...
This place truly is blessed.
My head hurts...
Are you awake?
Why would you bolt upright like that...?
I just... well... sorry.
I came to wake you because the
elders had all returned home.
It's already afternoon?
Looking back on it now,
it really was like I spent the night
in some sort of fairy tale...
But it wasn't a fairy tale. It was real.
It seems there's a great
deal I've yet to learn.
Did you sleep well, Sera?
Veor's beard?!
It grows back so quickly, I don't
usually bother with shaving, but...
You're reacting the same way.
I-I have no idea what you mean!
Now, let's have lunch.
Wh-What?!
Eat now, flirt later.
What is this? It's thick, and hot,
and kind of gamy... and juicy?
Dragon meat and herb sandwich,
on potato loaf.
It's from the Tsukebikeshi you killed.
Everyone else was eating it yesterday.
The bird?!
It was a dragon.
It takes a moment to get used to,
but it is quite good, that bird.
Dragon.
I'll take another.
That's quite an appetite...
We've got a bit of walking to do.
Are you ready, Sera?
There's someone who heard about you
this morning and wants to meet you.
An acquaintance of yours, apparently.
I can't imagine who I
might know around here...
Someone I crossed blades with before?
You could've waited in the house!
I was too excited to sit still.
It has truly been a long
time, Lady Serafina.
I heard you defended a family
that was attacked by a dragon,
and finding out
that you're as proud and courageous
as ever has me feeling nostalgic.
Sorry, who are you?
Well, I have changed a fair bit...
I'm Nyleia.
I served as a knight in the Eastern
Expedition under your command,
four years ago.
Do you remember me?
Nyleia from the Eastern Expedition...
Commander Lavillant.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I am Nyleia de Philomar,
at your service as a part of the Eastern
Expeditionary Force's First Division.
Well met.
I've been told one of the frontier
villages has come under attack!
Let's go, Nyleia!
Right!
Wretched barbarians.
Their struggle will be meaningless!
Are you all right, Nyleia?!
I'm fine. But we need to
press them, quickly...
Nyleia!
Nyleia?!
My old subordinate,
Viscount Philomar's daughter?!
I thought you were dead!
I can see why you'd be surprised.
And that belly... are you... with child?
This will be my second.
A second?!
I mean, surely things can change
a lot in four years, but...
This is a bit too much
for me to comprehend!
It is a something of a long
story... Let's talk inside.
When my husband told me about
the Crystal Helmet last night,
I thought it had to be you.
That helmet did tend to draw attention,
for better or worse...
And you have a husband, eh?
I certainly do.
I was proposed to by the
man who defeated me.
And in spite of it all,
I've made a life here...
I honestly have trouble
believing it at times.
My time in the expeditionary force
feels like another person's life.
I see.
I have to ask, why did
you call out to Veor?
He seems to be the son of
someone in authority...
Is it wise to have him
running errands for you?
You'll find it's not quite the same
as in the west, in that sense.
And young Veor stands out so much...
I find myself turning to him for help.
He does stand out, but...
"Young" Veor?
What is it, Sera?
You're not that young.
Lady Serafina, Veor's only 18 years old.
But have you seen his beard?!
I can't help what my body does...
Lady Nyleia is my cousin's wife.
So she's a distant relative.
That's true. Being family is part of it.
Hang on, you're 18?! You?!
Yes. Did I not mention that?
You did not!
And Lady Serafina turns 26 this—
Do not!
The prime of womanhood!
That suits me just fine.
I-I don't appreciate that statement
from someone younger than me!
Or is that your way of
bragging about your youth?
No. If anything, I wish
I was born a bit earlier.
Why is that?
I could've met you sooner, and you
wouldn't fret about the age difference.
Of all the ridiculous things to say...
Listen to me closely, Veor.
Don't assume our hypothetical alternate
encounter would end in your favor.
No matter when,
I will never be your bride!
My lady, Serafina de Lavillant,
I offer a heartfelt apology.
The arrogance of my youth...
was clearly an unintended insult
to you, a fellow warrior.
As long as you understand.
Why did Master Veor randomly apologize?
Well...
When Lady Serafina was captured,
what kind of injury did she have?
Nothing in particular.
She managed to fight until
her sword shattered.
Then it wasn't shattered, but lasted
to the point of giving out...
Veor's in the wrong, then.
Listen well.
Knights make it a point of courtesy,
and warriors make it a point of pride,
to fight to the death, with no mercy.
And when two foes are evenly matched,
they fight until one is
no longer able to go on.
But Veor, whose blows can
shatter stone and slay dragons,
fought until her weapon,
which was ordinary steel, expired,
yet was unable to land a single blow...
In other words, it took an advantage in
equipment to let him fight her evenly,
and beyond that, he had to rely on
his stamina to draw out a victory.
If he had left himself
open for even a moment...
All that said, war is about making do
with the best weapons available to you,
and he apparently didn't use
his Thundering Voice, either...
Still, it's presumptuous to assume
he'd win a second battle,
considering it wasn't definitive
the first time around.
I'm embarrassed enough.
Could you show some mercy?
He's never made that face before...
I can't believe I'm paying
such close attention to him.
I'd like to apologize again, Sera,
as well as giving my thanks to
fortune for granting me my victory!
F-Fine.
What was that?! She obviously likes him!
I just wish they'd get on with it already.
You two aren't mincing
words anymore, are you?!
We're back!
Oh, Vidal, welcome home.
Yeah.
Hey, it's Veo!
I'm too old to get called that, Vido.
Look at you, visiting with the
Crystal Helmet and Cersei.
Thanks for having us.
Make yourselves at home.
Mother!
Welcome home!
You should've seen him
out there running today.
Really? It won't be long before we'll
need to get him a wooden sword.
Nyleia's husband and son...
Lady Serafina.
I've accepted no shortage of scorn
for becoming a knight as a woman...
But serving and fighting under
you has made something clear.
I was given a duty by God
to fight for my homeland.
I will dedicate myself
to bettering the people.
To claiming barbarian territory
and watering it with their savage blood,
so that our crops may grow.
You really have changed, Nyleia.
But you look so much happier than
I can ever remember you being...
It's nice.
Oh, no! That was... I didn't mean to.
You didn't mean to...?
I didn't mean what I said, is all.
Sera?
The Frozen Lavillant looks
hot under the collar...
Reminds me of when we were newlyweds!
This calls for celebratory drinks.
I hope you're ready, Veo!
Newlyweds?! I'm not...
I didn't expect to be
celebrating two days in a row.
These two days have made
something abundantly clear.
I knew nothing about this place.
Who lives here, what kind
of culture they have...
I marched, and fought against them,
without knowing any of it.
Your warriors have families,
just like the knights of Illdoren...
But I didn't think of it,
and tried to ignore the obvious fact.
I called you barbarians and savages.
Using that as justification
for an invasion,
acting as if it was morally righteous...
Believing it was what
was best for my people.
Sera...
I thought you were an
enemy, worthy of hate.
But knowing you as a person,
it's clear that's wrong.
But even then... I am a knight,
and a noble of Illdoren.
My yearning to save my barren homeland
and its suffering people remains.
If I take home what I've learned here,
I may be able to make that happen.
Which is why I have no intention
of becoming your wife.
That stands to reason...
Still, that is only how I
feel in light of my duties.
Which is to say, uh... well...
Speaking as an individual,
I don't think it sounds bad... Veor.
Sera!
This is too much!
You know, I'm certain now. For all
your sincerity, you don't play fair.
How was that not fair?!
You're not even aware of it...
What a state of affairs.
What are you on about?!
Translation: Lee Francis
Timing: Andy Ellis
Editing: Zachary Carlysle
Quality Control: Salem Alabanza
Translation Check: Sho Stifler
Another fine meal!
You're in a good mood.
Well, can you blame me, after how
charming you were last night?
I-I wasn't trying to...
It was the liquor talking!
Oh, I see. Then it's not
how you truly feel...
You...!
Do you think I'm shameless enough to say
something so brazen and not mean it?!
What I said last night were
my true and honest feelings!
Do not insult me!
And now she's saying it without any booze.
To be so honest while sober...
it's really unfair how lovely you are.
You said the same thing yesterday!